Dorothy C. Miller
Archives of American Art, Smithsonian Institution
- Rockefeller Family Art Collections, circa 1949-1985, Series 3:; (Boxes 8-12, 25; 3.9 linear ft.)
  - Nelson A. Rockefeller, circa 1949-1985, 3.1:
    - Nelson A. Rockefeller Collection Book (Box 9)
      - Records of Photo Requests for Book, 1968-1978, (4 folders) (Box 11, Folder 28-31)
      - Records of Photos to Accompany Text, circa 1979 (Box 11, Folder 32)
      - Text Drafts (by Russell), 1971, circa 1978 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      - Artwork, Photographs of, circa 1963, (From Box 10, F 14) (Box 25 (sol))
  - Other Rockefeller Family Members, 1956-1981, 3.2:
    Miller's consulting work with Blanchette Rockefeller (Mrs. John D. Rockefeller, III) and David and Peggy Rockefeller is documented here. Files relating to Blanchette Rockefeller primarily concern her purchases from the Museum of Modern Art's 1965 exhibition The New Japanese Painting and Sculpture.
    Miller's notes and correspondence with David and Peggy Rockefeller are about her suggestions for acquisitions. Of particular interest is Miller's 1976 letter to David Rockefeller in which she recalls her first encounter with Morris Graves and seeing his artwork for the first time. Rockefeller purchased Graves's painting Shore Birds in 1977.
    Also found here is correspondence relating to David Rockefeller's acquisitions from the Edith G. Halpert collection sold at auction in 1973 by Parke-Bernet. Additional files document Miller's research into acquisitions of folk art for the Rockefellers and the Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection. Additional documentation of Miller's work for David Rockefeller in relation to the Rockefeller University Collection is found in the next subseries.
    - Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Folk Art Collection, 1956-1979 (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Rockefeller, Blanchette (Mrs. John D., III), 1965-1976, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 2-3)
    - Rockefeller, David, Correspondence and Notes, 1973-1981, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 4-5)
    - Rockefeller, David, Edith G. Halpert Collection Acquisitions, 1972-1973, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 6-7)
    - Rockefeller, David, Weathervane Acquisitions, 1972-1977, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 8-9)
    - Rockefeller Family, News Clippings, 1969-1980 (Box 12, Folder 10)
- Rockefeller University Collection, 1923-1984, Series 4:; (Boxes 12-13, OV 27; 1.0 linear ft.)
  Miller's curatorial and consulting work with the Rockefeller University (formerly Rockefeller Institute) committee and David Rockefeller to build an art collection for the University's Abby Aldrich Rockefeller Hall are arranged here. These include correspondence, notes, printed material, photographs and slides; artists' files, an exhibition file, design plans.
  - Rockefeller Institute Curatorial Files (Box 12)
    - Curatorial Files, 1957-1959, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 11-13)
    - Curatorial Files, circa 1960-1962 (Box 12, Folder 14)
    - Curatorial Files, 1970-1972, (2 folders) (Box 12, Folder 15-16)
    - Curatorial Files, 1972-1975 (Box 12, Folder 17)
    - Curatorial Files, 1978 (Box 12, Folder 18)
    - Curatorial Files, 1969-1970 (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Curatorial Files, 1971-1978 (Box 12, Folder 20)
    - Curatorial Files, 1974-1984, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 21-23)
  - Rockefeller University Curatorial Files (Box 12)
    - 17th Floor, circa 1971-circa 1977, (3 folders) (Box 12, Folder 24-26)
    - 17th Floor Architectural Plans, 1972, (see OV 27) (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - Mildred Burrage, circa 1972-circa 1983, (4 folders) (Box 12, Folder 28-31)
    - Mildred Burrage Exhibition, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Margaret Ann Coggswell, 1975-1981 (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Jacques Louis David, 1955-1976, (4 folders) (Box 13, Folder 3-6)
    - Insurance, 1970-1980 (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Marguerite S. Lederburg, 1980 (Box 13, Folder 8)
    - Minoru Niizuma, 1971-1973 (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - David Plowden, 1975-1976 (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - President's House, 1975-1980 (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Ann Roudebush Art Collection, 1923-1983 (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Bruce Tippett, 1966-1976, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 13-14)
    - Oversized 17th Floor Architectural Plans, 1972, (From Box 12, F 27) (Box OV 27)
- Chase Manhattan Bank Art Collection Committee, 1959-circa 1985, Series 5:; (Boxes 13-14, 26; 1.4 linear ft.)
  This series documents Miller's work as an art consultant to the Chase Manhattan Bank and founding member of the bank's art collection committee in 1959. Files here trace the development of the Chase collection from the early 1960s to the mid 1980s.
  Records include a series of files labeled "Catalogs of Artwork" which provide detailed lists of all artwork; committee files containing correspondence and memoranda between members of the art committee including Miller, Alfred Barr, Robert Hale, Perry Rathbone, David Rockefeller (then the bank's president) and James Johnson Sweeney; committee meeting minutes, agendas, and reports; catalogs of the bank's acquisitions and collection; and news clippings. There is also correspondence with the Chase curator Mary Lanier and art institutions and galleries.
  A draft of Miller's text for the bank's published catalog of essays, Art At Work: Chase Manhattan Bank Collection is filed in this series, as well as an interview transcript with Miller conducted by Peter Morin of the High Museum of Art in Atlanta, Georgia, about the exhibition, Chase Manhattan: the First 10 Years of Collecting, 1959-1969.
  - Art At Work: The Chase Manhattan Collection, Miller's Draft Text, circa 1985 (Box 13, Folder 15)
  - Catalog of Artwork, circa 1960-circa 1965, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 16-17)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 18)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 19)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1969, (2 folders) (Box 13, Folder 20-21)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1970, (see Box 26) (Box 13, Folder 22)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1974, (see Box 26) (Box 13, Folder 23)
  - Catalog of Artwork, 1978, (3 folders) (Box 13, Folder 24-26)
  - Committee Files, 1959 (Box 13, Folder 27)
  - Committee Files, 1960 (Box 13, Folder 28)
  - Committee Files, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 29)
  - Committee Files, 1961-1962 (Box 13, Folder 30)
  - Committee Files, 1963-1964 (Box 13, Folder 31)
  - Committee Files, 1965 (Box 13, Folder 32)
  - Committee Files, 1966 (Box 13, Folder 33)
  - Committee Files, 1967, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 1-2)
  - Committee Files, 1967-1968 (Box 14, Folder 3)
  - Committee Files, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Committee Files, 1969 (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Committee Files, 1970 (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Committee Files, 1971-1972 (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Committee Files, 1973 (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Committee Files, 1974 (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Committee Files, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Committee Files, 1976-1978 (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Committee Files, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Committee Files, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 13)
  - Committee Files, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 14)
  - Committee Files, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 15)
  - Committee Files, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 16)
  - Committee Files, 1983-1984 (Box 14, Folder 17)
  - Finch College Exhibition: Art from the Chase Manhattan Bank Collection, 1971 (Box 14, Folder 18)
  - Interview Transcript, 1982 (Box 14, Folder 19)
  - Oversized Catalog of Artwork, 1970, (From Box 13, F 22) (Box 26 (sol))
  - Oversized Catalog of Artwork, 1974, (From Box 13, F 23) (Box 26 (sol))
- Port Authority of New York and New Jersey Art Committee, circa 1965-1987, Series 6:; (Boxes 14-15, OV 27; 0.8 linear ft.)
  In 1969 Executive Director of the Port Authority of New York and New Jersey (PANJY) Austin J. Tobin established a committee to commission and acquire artwork for PANJY's facilities and hired Miller as the primary art consultant. Files are found here that document Miller's work with the committee, including committee meeting minutes and agendas, correspondence and notes, printed materials, photographs.
  Several files are related to Miller's work with the committee for selecting artwork for the World Trade Center in the early 1970s. These contain letters from Alexander Calder discussing the purchase of Calder's World Trade Center Stabile, also known as Three Wings and The Cockeyed Propeller which was originally commissioned for the entrance to 1 World Trade Center on West Street, but was moved around the plaza over time. One of Calder's letters is illustrated with a picture indicating how he wanted the stabile's "feet" to be installed. Also found here are several photographs of Calder and his mobiles and stabiles, letters from Joan Miró, Chryssa, and photographs of artwork by other artists.
  One file in this series contains writings by Miller concerning the collections of the PANJY.
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1969-1972 (Box 14, Folder 20)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1973-1977 (Box 14, Folder 21)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1978 (Box 14, Folder 22)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1979 (Box 14, Folder 23)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1980 (Box 14, Folder 24)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1981 (Box 14, Folder 25)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1982-1983 (Box 14, Folder 26)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1984 (Box 14, Folder 27)
  - Agenda and Minutes, 1985-1987 (Box 14, Folder 28)
  - Art For The Public, circa 1979-1984, (2 folders) (Box 14, Folder 29-30)
  - General Files, circa 1965-circa 1967 (Box 14, Folder 31)
  - General Files, circa 1968-circa 1975, (3 folders) (Box 14, Folder 32-34)
  - General Files, 1974-1976 (Box 15, Folder 1)
  - General Files, 1976-1978 (Box 15, Folder 2)
  - General Files, 1978-1985, (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 3-5)
  - World Trade Center, circa 1965 (Box 15, Folder 6)
  - World Trade Center, circa 1965-circa 1970, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 7-8)
  - World Trade Center, 1970-1971, (see also OV 27) (Box 15, Folder 9)
  - World Trade Center, 1972-1980 (Box 15, Folder 10)
  - Oversized World Trade Center, Tower B Main Lobby Plan and Elevation, 1970, (From Box 15, F 9) (Box OV 27)
- Other Corporate and Private Clients, 1968-1984, Series 7:; (Boxes 15-16; 1.3 linear ft.)
  Miller's consulting work with other corporate and private clients is documented here with correspondence, printed material, sketches, photographs, and slides.
  - Corporate Clients (Box 15)
    - Amstar Corporation, 1969-1972, (3 folders) (Box 15, Folder 11-13)
    - Amstar Corporation, 1971 (Box 15, Folder 14)
    - Amstar Corporation, 1971-1974 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Amstar Corporation, 1972-1977 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Fidelity International Bank, 1973-1977 (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - First National Bank of Tampa, 1972-1973 (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - First National City Bank, 1970-1973, (2 folders) (Box 15, Folder 19-20)
    - First National City Bank, 1974-1977 (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Inmont Corporation, 1968-1969 (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Inmont Corporation, 1969-1971 (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Inmont Corporation, 1970-1975 (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Inmont Corporation, circa 1970s-1984 (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Paul, Weiss, Rifkind, Wharton & Garrison, 1969, 1976 (Box 15, Folder 26)
    - Pepsico Incorporated, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - United Mutual Savings Bank, 1971-1972 (Box 15, Folder 28)
  - Private Clients (Box 16)
    - Burden, William A. M., 1970 (Box 16, Folder 1)
    - Englehard, Jane, 1969-1973, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 2-3)
    - Englehard, Jane, 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 4)
    - Englehard, Jane, 1976-1980 (Box 16, Folder 5)
    - Grossman, Isobel, 1970-1975 (Box 16, Folder 6)
    - Lombard, Jane, circa 1971-circa 1984 (Box 16, Folder 7)
    - Lombard, Jane, 1971-1974, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 8-9)
    - Lombard, Jane, 1975-1977, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 10-11)
    - Lombard, Jane, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 12)
    - Lombard, Jane, 1978-1984 (Box 16, Folder 13)
    - Parkinson, Eliza, 1969-1977 (Box 16, Folder 14)
    - Seeligson, Arthur A., Jr., and Linda N., 1969-1972, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 15-16)
    - Seeligson, Arthur A., Jr., and Linda N., 1973-1975 (Box 16, Folder 17)
    - Seeligson, Arthur A., Jr., and Linda N., 1976-1980 (Box 16, Folder 18)
    - Seeligson, Arthur A., Jr., and Linda N., circa 1969-circa 1980 (Box 16, Folder 19)
    - Stern, Edith, 1978-1979 (Box 16, Folder 20)
  - Corporate and Private Clients, Miscellaneous, 1971-1979 (Box 16, Folder 21)
  - Miscellaneous Notes, circa 1970-circa 1983 (Box 16, Folder 22)
- Other Boards, Committees and Commissions, 1925, 1949-1985, Series 8:; (Boxes 16-20; 3.6 linear ft.)
  Following her retirement from the Museum of Modern Art, Miller served on a variety of public and private boards, commissions, and committees for art museums and institutions. The majority of these files contain correspondence, meeting minutes and reports, notes, legal records, and printed material.
  The series is arranged as 6 subseries by museum or organization:
  8.1: Empire State Plaza Art Commission, 1965-1978
  8.2: Hancock Shaker Village, Shaker Community, Inc., Board of Trustees, 1949-1985
  8.3: Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden Board of Trustees, 1976-1985
  8.4: Mark Rothko Foundation, Inc., Board of Directors, 1966-1985
  8.5: Museum of American Folk Art Board of Trustees, 1962-1969
  8.6: Smith College Museum of Art Visiting Committee, 1925, 1961-1984
  - Empire State Plaza Art Commission, 1965-1978, 8.1
    Found here are records of Miller's activities as one of five members of the Art Commission for the Empire State Plaza (also known as the South Mall) in Albany, New York, built under the governorship of Nelson A. Rockefeller between 1965 and 1978. The files include scattered correspondence with artists Chryssa, Jason Seley, Daniel LaRue Johnson, and Gene Davis.
    - General, 1965-1974, (2 folders) (Box 16, Folder 23-24)
    - General, 1968-1970 (Box 16, Folder 25)
    - General, 1970-1973 (Box 16, Folder 26)
    - General, 1976-1978 (Box 16, Folder 27)
    - Meeting Records, 1968-1973 (Box 16, Folder 28)
    - News Clippings, 1970-1976 (Box 16, Folder 29)
    - Photos of Artwork in Collection (incomplete), circa 1970s (Box 16, Folder 30)
    - Seley, Jason, 1969-1972 (Box 16, Folder 31)
  - Hancock Shaker Village, Shaker Community, Inc., Board of Trustees, 1949-1985, 8.2:
    Miller's work as a member of the Board of Trustees of Shaker Community, Inc. which oversaw the operations of Hancock Shaker Village in Massachusetts is documented here through correspondence with village founder Amy Bess Miller, notes; meeting minutes and other meeting materials; financial records; and printed material. Trustee files for 1961 contain a letter to Miller from Andrew Wyeth.
    - General, 1949-1963 (Box 17, Folder 1)
    - General, 1956-1963 (Box 17, Folder 2)
    - General, 1970-1985 (Box 17, Folder 3)
    - Trustee Files, 1959-1962, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 4-5)
    - Trustee Files, 1960-1961 (Box 17, Folder 6)
    - Trustee Files, 1962-1963 (Box 17, Folder 7)
    - Trustee Files, 1963-1964 (Box 17, Folder 8)
    - Trustee Files, 1965-1966, (2 folders) (Box 17, Folder 9-10)
    - Trustee Files, 1967-1968 (Box 17, Folder 11)
    - Trustee Files, 1968-1969 (Box 17, Folder 12)
    - Trustee Files, 1970-1972 (Box 17, Folder 13)
    - Trustee Files, 1972-1974 (Box 17, Folder 14)
    - Trustee Files, 1974-1976 (Box 17, Folder 15)
    - Trustee Files, 1977-1979 (Box 17, Folder 16)
    - Trustee Files, 1979-1980 (Box 17, Folder 17)
    - Trustee Files, 1980-1981 (Box 17, Folder 18)
    - Trustee Files, 1981-1982 (Box 17, Folder 19)
    - Trustee Files, 1982-1983 (Box 17, Folder 20)
    - Trustee Files, 1983-1985 (Box 17, Folder 21)
  - Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden Board of Trustees, 1976-1985, 8.3:
    Miller served on the Board of Trustees for the Hirshhorn Museum and Sculpture Garden from 1976 - 1984. Found here are files relating to her work as a trustee.
    - Collections Management Policy, 1981 (Box 17, Folder 23)
    - Committee on Collections Meetings, 1978, 1981, 1983 (Box 17, Folder 24)
    - Committee on Exhibitions Meetings, 1976 (Box 17, Folder 25)
    - Committee on Exhibitions Meetings, 1977 (Box 17, Folder 26)
    - Committee on Exhibitions Meetings, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 1)
    - Committee on Exhibitions Meetings, 1980-1983, (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 2-4)
    - Correspondence, 1976-1984 (Box 18, Folder 5)
    - Exhibition Announcements and Catalogs, 1976-1984 (Box 18, Folder 6)
    - National Building Museum, 1980-1981 (Box 18, Folder 7)
    - News Clippings, 1976-1982, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 8-9)
    - Press Releases, 1976-1985, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 10-11)
    - Travel Vouchers, 1976-1980 (Box 18, Folder 12)
    - Trustee Files, 1976 (Box 18, Folder 13)
    - Trustee Files, 1976-1977 (Box 18, Folder 14)
    - Trustee Files, 1977, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 15-16)
    - Trustee Files, 1978 (Box 18, Folder 17)
    - Trustee Files, 1979, (3 folders) (Box 18, Folder 18-20)
    - Trustee Files, 1980, (2 folders) (Box 18, Folder 21-22)
    - Trustee Files, 1981 (Box 18, Folder 23)
    - Trustee Files, 1982 (Box 18, Folder 24)
    - Trustee Files, 1983 (Box 18, Folder 25)
    - Trustee Files, 1984 (Box 18, Folder 26)
  - Mark Rothko Foundation, Inc., Board of Directors, 1966-1985, 8.4:
    Dorothy Miller served as a member of the Board of Directors of the Mark Rothko Foundation following a major lawsuit that ensued after Rothko's death in 1970 between the family, executors of the estate, and Marlborough Gallery. In 1977, the litigation ended with Rothko Prizel gaining control of the estate and re-establishing the foundation and its board. Files arranged here document the foundation's efforts to rebuild and determine the best use of Rothko's paintings for the public interest.
    - Board Files, 1976, (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 1-3)
    - Board Files, 1976-1977, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 4-5)
    - Board Files, 1977, (3 folders) (Box 19, Folder 6-8)
    - Board Files, 1977-1978 (Box 19, Folder 9)
    - Board Files, 1978-1980, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 10-11)
    - Board Files, 1979-1980 (Box 19, Folder 12)
    - Board Files, 1980 (Box 19, Folder 13)
    - Board Files, 1981, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 14-15)
    - Board Files, 1982-1983, (2 folders) (Box 19, Folder 16-17)
    - Board Files, 1982-1985 (Box 19, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence, 1966-1982 (Box 19, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence, 1982-1984 (Box 19, Folder 20)
    - Inventory of Artwork in Rothko Estate, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 21)
    - Printed Material, Gustave Harrow, 1977, 1979 (Box 19, Folder 22)
    - Printed Material, News Clippings, 1971-1985 (Box 19, Folder 23)
  - Museum of American Folk Art Board of Trustees, 1962-1969, 8.5:
    Found here is one folder of material with scattered documentation of Miller's work as a member of the board of trustees for the Museum of American Folk Art in New York City.
    - Museum of American Folk Art, 1962-1969 (Box 19, Folder 24)
  - Smith College Museum of Art Visiting Committee, 1925, 1961-1984, 8.6:
    Dorothy Miller's files concerning her work on the Smith College Museum of Art Visiting Committee are arranged here.
    - Committee Files, 1961-1968 (Box 20, Folder 1)
    - Committee Files, 1969 (Box 20, Folder 2)
    - Committee Files, 1970-1971 (Box 20, Folder 3)
    - Committee Files, 1971-1972 (Box 20, Folder 4)
    - Committee Files, 1972-1973 (Box 20, Folder 5)
    - Committee Files, 1973-1974 (Box 20, Folder 6)
    - Committee Files, 1974-1975 (Box 20, Folder 7)
    - Committee Files, 1975-1976 (Box 20, Folder 8)
    - Committee Files, 1977-1984 (Box 20, Folder 9)
    - Smith College Newsletter, 1925 (Box 20, Folder 10)
- Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project Files, 1935-1979, Series 9:; (Box 20, OV 27; 0.5 linear ft.)
  Some of Holger Cahill's files relating to his work as director of the Federal Art Project (FAP) of the Works Progress Administration (WPA) remained with Dorothy Miller, including a series of essays written primarily by FAP artists which Cahill intended to publish, but had not before his death in 1960. This series contains both Cahill's files and Miller's files relating to subsequent FAP research efforts by others. There are two folders of correspondence and other material concerning Miller's work with art historian Francis O'Connor in collecting, organizing, and editing the FAP artist essays that Cahill had saved and which were ultimately published as Art for the Millions: Essays from the 1930s by Artists and Administrators of the Works Progress Administration Federal Art Project (Boston: New York Graphic Society, 1975). In the mid-1960s Miller began donating Cahill's FAP records to the Archives of American Art and scattered correspondence related to this disposition can be found here.
  Miller also worked with the Newark Museum in 1978-1979 on the exhibition Murals Without Walls which celebrated the recovery of two large panels of Arshile Gorky's "lost" murals painted for the Newark Airport in 1936-1937 under the FAP. There are files of Miller's correspondence with the museum about the project wherein she provided information about the Gorky murals from Cahill's FAP files.
  Additional files document inquiries relating to poster artists and referrals that Miller made to the Office of War Information Graphics Division following the closure of the FAP; an exhibition The Thirties: Reaction to a Crisis held at the Lowe Art Center in April 1974; and a folder of five copies of letters from Holger Cahill to artist Mitchell Siporin. There is also a folder containing copies of a text written by Miller for an exhibition she organized and was circulated by the Museum of Modern Art entitled The U.S. Government Art Projects: Some Distinguished Alumni.
  - Arshile Gorky Murals, 1936-1979, (3 folders) (Box 20, Folder 11-13)
  - Art For The Millions, 1935-1976, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 14-15)
  - Cahill Letters to Mitchell Siporin, 1937-1945 (Box 20, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence, 1936-1978, (4 folders) (Box 20, Folder 17-20)
  - Correspondence, Contreras, Belisario R. (researcher), 1963-1968 (Box 20, Folder 21)
  - Office of War Information Graphics Division, 1941-1943, (2 folders; see also OV 27) (Box 20, Folder 22-23)
  - The U. S. Government Art Projects: Some Distinguished Alumni, Exhibition (1963-1964: Museum of Modern Art), circa 1963 (Box 20, Folder 24)
  - The Thirties: Reaction to a Crisis Exhibition (1974: Lowe Art Center), 1969-1979 (Box 20, Folder 25)
  - Oversized Office of War Information Graphics Division Sheet of Stamps, 1943, (From Box 20, F 23) (Box OV 27)
- Edward Hicks Catalog, 1934-1984, Series 10:; (Boxes 20-22; 21.5 linear ft.)
  This series documents Miller's collaborative work with Eleanore Price Mather to compile and publish the monograph Edward Hicks: His Peaceable Kingdoms and Other Paintings (University of Delaware Press, Newark, 1983).
  Materials include correspondence between Miller and Mather and others, notes, Christmas cards with reproductions of artwork by Hicks, contract files, lists, research files, printed material, and annotated photographs of artwork.
  - Correspondence (Box 20)
    - Mather, Eleanor Price, 1959-1984, (2 folders) (Box 20, Folder 26-27)
    - Correspondents A-B, 1934-1979 (Box 20, Folder 28)
    - Correspondents C, 1938-1979 (Box 20, Folder 29)
    - Correspondents D-G, 1938-1981 (Box 20, Folder 30)
    - Correspondents H-L, 1938-1973 (Box 20, Folder 31)
    - Correspondents M-R, 1938-1976 (Box 21, Folder 1)
    - Correspondents S-V, 1938-1975 (Box 21, Folder 2)
    - Correspondents W-Y, 1959-1977 (Box 21, Folder 3)
    - Photograph Requests, 1975 (Box 21, Folder 4)
    - Publication by Associated University Presses, 1980-1983 (Box 21, Folder 5)
  - Greeting Cards, circa 1938-circa 1970s (Box 21, Folder 6)
  - Hicks Bibliographies, circa 20th century (Box 21, Folder 7)
  - Listings for Catalog, 1978, (2 folders) (Box 21, Folder 8-9)
  - Notes for Catalog by L. L. Beans "The Life and Work of Edward Hicks," 1949-1951 (Box 21, Folder 10)